<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Thoughts on Anthony's blog</title><link>https://jinggqu.github.io/categories/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in Thoughts on Anthony's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 21:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jinggqu.github.io/categories/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Few Thoughts</title><link>https://jinggqu.github.io/posts/a-few-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 21:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://jinggqu.github.io/posts/a-few-thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="a-few-thoughts"&gt;A Few Thoughts
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="proof-you-can-do-hard-things"&gt;Proof You Can Do Hard Things
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you’re not someone who knows they can do hard things, find a way to prove it to yourself. Build a habit, learn a skill, create something, whatever it is that turns your default stance on challenges from “that seems hard” to “I can figure it out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a class="link" href="https://blog.nateliason.com/p/proof-you-can-do-hard-things" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://blog.nateliason.com/p/proof-you-can-do-hard-things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="stop-obsessing-over-tools"&gt;Stop Obsessing Over Tools
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often see people in a constant search for the best note taking app. Or the best Linux distro and desktop setup. Or the best AI tool to enhance productivity. Or the best game engine. And so on, you guys get the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This search takes you nowhere. Doing this doesn’t make you productive. You will never find the best or the most perfect setup. Settling for good enough is most often the best thing you do. Otherwise you’ll find yourself productive in the search of being productive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a class="link" href="https://plug-world.com/posts/stop-obsessing-over-tools/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://plug-world.com/posts/stop-obsessing-over-tools/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="重来更为简单有效的商业思维"&gt;重来：更为简单有效的商业思维
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;From chapter 音乐就在你的指尖流淌&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;吉他大师说：“音乐就在你的指尖流淌。”就算你买了和艾迪·范·海伦（Eddie Van Halen）一样的吉他、效果踏板、扩音器，但是当你用这套装备来演奏时，弹出来的依然是你自己的风格。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;同理，给艾迪配一套从当铺倒腾出来的劣质装备，人家一出手，你还是能听出是艾迪·范·海伦的水平。好的装备的确能带来一些帮助，但事实是，你的演奏水平是由你自己的手指决定的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;人们总忍不住要执着于工具，而不关注要用这些工具去做的事情。你见过这类人：能玩转一大堆震撼的艺术字体和漂亮的 Photoshop 滤镜效果的设计师，却不知道该表达什么。业余摄影爱好者总为使用胶片相机还是数码相机而争论不休，却没人关注拍出绝妙照片的决定因素是什么。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;很多业余高尔夫球手执着于加入昂贵的俱乐部，但是真正重要的是如何挥杆，而不是加入哪个俱乐部。就算让老虎伍兹加入廉价的俱乐部，他也照样能摆平你。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;人们把装备当作取胜的法宝，却不愿意花时间去练习，于是一直泡在专业器材店里。他们想要寻找捷径，然而，最好的工具不是用在普通领域的。而且你在起步阶段肯定用不上它。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在商业领域，太多人纠结于工具的好坏、软件技巧、规模大小、舒适的办公环境、豪华的家具以及其他浮华的东西，而不去关注真正的要点。真正的要点就是怎样赢得客户、如何赢利。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;我们还可以看到一些人想要通过博客、播客或拍摄纪录片来宣传他们的业务，却受困于不知选择什么工具。真正要紧的是宣传的内容。你可以花大手笔购买超级棒的设备，但是如果没有什么内容可表达……那么，你还真没什么可说的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;就用你现在手头有的或者能负担得起的，然后开始做吧。工具不重要，就用现有的工具也可以做得一样棒，音乐就在你的指尖流淌。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a class="link" href="https://book.douban.com/subject/30184215/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://book.douban.com/subject/30184215/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>